[music]
Tôi luôn nói với mọi người về
tâm lý của một vận động viên thể hình,
Họ buộc phải có--một thứ gì đó
thôi thúc bên trong họ.
Họ không thể bình thường.
[music]
Họ không bao giờ thỏa mãn
với hiện tại
vì họ luôn luôn muốn bản thân
tốt hơn.
Họ luôn muốn một hình thể đẹp hơn
hiện tại.
Họ bắt buộc phải đẩy bản thân
liên tục vượt qua giới hạn.
Một số người có cơ địa tiềm tàng
trở thành người có hình thể đẹp nhất trên thế giới
nhưng họ không có đủ sự kiên quyết
để đạt được điều đó.
Thật sự mà nói, thì bạn phải..
Tôi nghĩ là, phải có một chút điên.
[music]
Bạn sẽ không hiểu
lợi thế để là một người bình thường
cho đến khi bạn nhìn vào ai đó như tôi,
người không thể mặc được những bộ quần áo bình thường
không thể ăn những thức ăn người thường,
không thể lái một chiếc xe có kích thước của người thường,
Không thể ngồi ghế có kích cỡ phổ thông khi lên máy bay
đi nước ngoài và cố ngủ
trên một cái giường khách sạn nhỏ xíu
cố gắng ngồi lọt vào cái bồn tắm nhỏ xíu trong khách sạn
Rất khó để đi ra ngoài ăn uống
và mua sắm như người bình thường
Rất khó để đi du lịch.
So I mean, when
you're 290 pounds,
it's very difficult
to do a lot of things.
You know, you're so abnormal, I
mean, as compared to what people
are used to seeing, people laugh
'cause they just never see
anyone so huge, you know.
It's hard to hide it.
And I'm, you know, I don't
wear big baggy clothes.
A lot of times, I wear more
form-fitting stuff and,
you know, people don't--
it's not the norm.
You have certain places where
you grow up and you're like,
"I want to be there."
I mean, this is one
of those places.
I came to Vegas for
the first time in '97.
I fell in love
with it, you know?
And that was before it was built
up even the way it is now.
But what other place can you go
and 24 hours a day you just wake
up and decide I want to go do
this or I want to go do that?
Like, I want to eat.
I want to go work out.
I want to go see
a movie, you know,
I want to go to the supermarket.
I want to go eat at this
restaurant, you know?
It's just--you can do anything
you want, pretty much.
You can have sushi
'til 6 in the morning.
I don't know any place in
the world really that does that
you know, on a consistent basis
that you can do that stuff.
I like the fast tempo of Vegas.
I couldn't live in
a slow environment.
People always ask me, "Are you
ever gonna move back to--"
I could never go back to
the slow pace, you know?
People ask me, "How do you
train and focus in Vegas
when there's so many outside
things pulling at you?"
And I think that I thrive on
that, I love to be able to know
that most people can't do that.
I mean, I love to be able to
have that at my fingertips
even though I never take
advantage of it.
It gives me more drive, being
in a place that's so actively
just crazy and I'm still
so focused on what I do.
It's kind of like the opposite
thinking a little bit, you know?
Here we are.
What's up, guys?
What up?
What's going on, man?
All right, pull ups.
Shirts off.
Kelly, you're getting
all swelled up.
Got to do something
for the Olympia.
Got to put Bodybuilding.com
in the back of my head.
Jay Cutler, trainer.
Yeah, it's been over
a couple some months.
So we're taking
it down again?
Just like we did last time?
Yeah, and you've got
to shave my face too.
Keep it tight?
Yeah, yeah.
Just a little tight, you know.
Tight at the bottom,
nice and clean, like.
Like a taper, right?
You know, I find myself
nowadays I don't even touch
my hair in the morning.
I get up.
That's what my hair looks like.
Then I jump in the pool.
Traveling and being Jay Cutler, it's not an easy thing.
Everywhere you go, you're
noticed and, of course,
you're in demand.
People say, "What do
you do for a living?"
I said, "I eat, sleep,
and train and that's it."
I kind of joke like that because
it does seem like that a lot of
times but there is some
fun built in there.
But I never looked at myself and
said, "I'm so obsessed," because
I always seem to have some sort
of balance in there and I always
realized that this is a career
and, obviously, if you go at it
full tilt all the time, you're
gonna burn yourself down so you
have to set a certain
pace for yourself.
To the point where you're
continually moving forward
and being great.
Very good or you want
something else on top?
No, that's good, right.
It's good.
Want some gel?
No, no, no.
I'm gonna take a
shower and clean up.
The Olympic chair.
Larry, I need your help.
What's going on with the shirts?
I just called
Kevin, actually.
So he is gonna call me back.
Everything should
be done this week.
I know, but "this
week" meaning what?
Tomorrow,
Wednesday the latest.
I would, honestly, I
believe they're done.
Usually, like, I
show up at, like--
When he wants to.
Between--no, 9 and 10.
When he wants to show up.
Nine and ten.
I don't--
It depends if he goes
out the night before.
No, I don't even
go out anymore.
I just work at night, that's it.
Every day it's
different, you know?
I say, "Pay this bill."
Okay, you've got to call these
people and, you know, it's,
literally I sit in the kitchen
and I scream to him,
"Hey," you know, "do
this, do that," you know?
So he's trying to do a job that
probably takes three or four
people and, for a 21-year-old
kid to be able to do that,
like, I mean, it takes
a lot of his time.
He works 6 days a week at
least, you know, sometimes 7.
You know, when you think
you've seen someone work hard,
like, "Oh, man, he works hard."
And then you meet someone like
Jay and you're like,
"This is a whole
'nother ball game."
You know, it's not like we're
operating a huge operation
over here.
I mean, running out of my house
and my garage and, yes, there's
a lot of space but, you know, we
have day-to-day things that we
need to get done and I'm
only home on certain times.
I traveled this year extensively
and we had 1 or 2 days to get
stuff done when I was home and
we rely on other people and it's
impossible to do that so
we try to do everything,
you know, on our own.
What did I overnight that?
I never overnight anything.
I know you like
to spend money, dude.
I see how much it cost.
It cost 35 bucks to
send a damn poster.
No, it doesn't.
What are you talking--
It cost you 35 bucks
to have one poster cost.
No, it didn't.
I saw it.
Did I not see it?
No it didn't cost me $35.
I'll show you right now.
What did I say about
that poster that day?
Don't lie.
Yeah, I did see
that it said that.
Oh, you said that
I have no choice.
That's what they choose.
Whoa.
What day--was it a
poster in a large box?
No, it's a poster.
By itself?
Yes.
And it cost $35?
Okay, I'll pull it up right
now and if it's $35,
then you can have my check.
You can have my whole check.
It's gonna come
out of your pay.
Don't start, Monique.
I'm in a bad mood that even
Larry said I came out in
a bad mood this morning.
And that's the thing, you run
with the crew and there's time
when we play and there's
time when we work.
And this is all business now.
I mean, this is--I admit
half my life is play time,
three-quarters of my life is
play time but when it comes down
to get the business and
the business is now, I mean,
there's no--we have
no time for fun.
You know, I've been
a four-time champ, you know,
and I've been 6-time runner-up
and I'm the greatest
bodybuilder ever.
There's no question.
I feel that I'm the greatest.
I still want to compete at my
best even at the age I'm at and,
you know, people say
"past your prime."
I mean, I don't know if
there's any past your prime.
When I'm still competitive you
don't want to think about that.
You're not gonna go and do a
show and say, "Well, I'm past my
prime, I'm just doing it for
the, you know, just to stand up
there."
That's not how an athlete or a
champion bodybuilder, you know,
trains for a
competition or things.
They always want to think about
winning and being the absolute
best.
[music]
There is no
failure at this point.
I mean, I've done it all.
There's never gonna be a day
that passes that I'm gonna step
out and people are gonna--aren't
gonna know who Jay Cutler is.
I don't see it ever happening.
Ron, what's up?
Oh, no...
I'm back in Vegas for the week
and I think Dave's coming
next--this coming weekend.
He's gonna shoot some training
stuff and then I shoot with
Bernell next week, I
think, for some features.
Hey, what's the name of that
pizza place next to Kyzen?
I like more lounge-type
places like Hyde Lounge
at Bellagio.
Monique?
Or Tryst at the Wynn.
No, I don't go to strip clubs.
I got a stripper
pole in my bedroom,
I don't need strip clubs.
[music]
You know, when you
have, like, you know,
30-something-inch thighs
and you've got, you know,
22-1/2-inch arms and you've
got a 19-inch neck and a broad
shoulder, it's difficult to find
things other than tank tops
and shorts.
Everything's custom.
I mean, I can't fit
into normal sleeves.
Obviously, the dress shirts are
tailored, you know, like,
the button-up shirts.
My suit jackets, I think, are 58
or 60 or something like that.
I mean, it's crazy.
If you look at what's
considered an ideal drop
to a manufacturer of suits,
it's a 6-inch drop.
That's the difference between
your chest and your waist.
I've got some guys that, you
know, are fairly serious
bodybuilders and they've
got a 10-inch drop.
And Jay has 20.
It kind of defies the physics of
what you can do with fabric,
you know, in a constructed sense
to go from here to here.
Right, Jay, you
ready to go to work?
I won't stop
and tell you now.
I'll remember.
Okay.
Fifty-four and you
were fifty-seven.
That's a big difference.
Feet together.
Wow, that's about
5 inches less, Jay.
That's pretty serious.
I won my first Olympia
heavier than I weigh right now.
I was competing against
Ronnie, you know, at 273.
I mean, when I came back
and won in 2009 I was 254.
It's all illusion, you know?
Thirty-seven.
Actual thigh, twenty-nine.
Nineteen.
Go ahead and flex.
Twenty-one-and-a-half.
You've lost a lot of weight
so we're gonna be doing
some different things here.
This thing'll be full
by the end of the day.
Yeah, it's hard to hide it.
You know, that's the one thing
about being a professional
bodybuilder, is where other
people can hide, you know,
athletes, unless they're,
like, real, real famous faces.
You just can't
hide the physique.
I mean, and the thing is is,
like, you know, a lot of
bodybuilders change from
on-season to off-season.
Like, I don't
change a whole lot.
I'm pretty much visible.
The hair's the same, the face
stays the same, you know?
And you know, I'm a unique look
for a lot of the bodybuilders,
you know?
You know, there's not a lot of
huge, you know, big, blond,
white guys, you know?
Oh, look at all those zits.
I'm gonna pop 'em after.
How bad has it
grown in now.
My God.
Bad?
You're like a Chia pet.
You know, I never had hair on
my back until I started shaving,
you know that?
When I got ready for my first
show when I was 18, it's like
when I started shaving my back,
it's like I turned into
a gorilla.
Larry told me to do Nair.
Less fuss.
I'm gonna tell him he
has to shave my armpits.
Yeah [laughing]
Hey, Larry!
I need your help.
Larry!
Dude, I need you to
shave my armpits.
Oh, no.
God, you're good, she's good.
You sure?
Yeah.
No, look at my armpits.
There's nothing in there.
And my lower
back, you did too?
You know, when you're my size
you never think you're small.
Like, I like the way I look now.
You know, I'm always in decent
shape and I always check myself
out.
I never look at my face though.
I mostly look at the physique,
you know, and flex the abs and,
ha, ha.
Ah, ah, right there.
As you've seen
the progression in almost
50 years of bodybuilding in
the Mr. Olympia Competition,
you know, we saw the days of
Arnold where they weren't so
conditioned or so big and
nowadays, I mean, the guys are
so big, they're so conditioned.
There's so many variables and
bodybuilding has become so
scientific and trying to tune
the body into, you know,
show the best conditioning
with the most size.
Ah, am I getting too big?
You know, bodies aren't made
to be as strong as I guess that
Mr. Olympia competitors become.
[rifle firing]
[laughing]
[music]
Jay, man, I'm gonna give you
a safety briefing before we
go on the range.
We're gonna treat every gun as
if it's loaded at all times,
even if you know it's unloaded.
Always keep your trigger finger
off the trigger 'til you're on
target and ready to fire.
And always keep the gun
pointed in a safe direction.
Pretty crazy.
If at any time, you hear
someone call out, "Cease fire,"
please stop shooting.
Take your finger off
the trigger, put the gun down
on the counter and step
back away from it.
Put your body weight forward.
It helps you to
absorb the recoil.
[rifle firing]
You're a gangster.
I know.
Single shot, full auto.
[rifle firing]
[pistol firing]
You can never teach
anyone training advice.
It's always the business.
'Cause everyone wants
to make the money.
They want to be a superstar
and look like a superstar.
The magazines expose you as
a superstar because you're
featured with the muscles
and the look, you know,
but financially they
want the back-up of that
and that's what I have.
I have all the tools to create
that and a lot of people have
come to me for that opportunity.
Yeah, we may stumble but we
always land higher and
get to where we need to be.
Even when I was smaller, I hate
to say small but I'd look at
these guys and still say, "I'm
still the best and still
the greatest and still th6e
biggest name in bodybuilding."
Stack 'em is the show.
Come on.
Let's go, Jay, come on.
Suck it up, suck it up,
suck it up, suck it up.
Mentally, you have to be,
I think, a little crazy.
People approach me and they
say, "Jay, what's the secret?
What's the secret?
What's the secret?"
I don't like to eat anything.
If you ask me what
my favorite food is,
I don't have a favorite food.
I don't look forward
to any meal at all.
You're a living legend,
that's what's amazing
about what I do.
Jay Cutler!
And I tell you, Jay Cutler's
the greatest of all time.